# **Nicholas Thomson**

Brooklyn, NY 11213 | 415-859-0848 | nicholasgraythomson@gmail.com Github | Medium | Personal Website

### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming, with a background as an Assistant Editor at Penguin Random House. Possess strong skills in editing, design, and project management that help tech companies build beautiful, responsive applications. A life spent learning has led me to many interesting places, including a cat circus in Moscow, where I was living one summer and studying Russian.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

# Orchid - Site | Github | Demo

A Spotify-like app designed for classical music

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Accessed the Spotify API using the rSpotify gem to allow users to play songs in-browser
- Built and seeded a database using the Open Opus API to provide users with an encyclopedic collection of data
- Employed Material UI to style components for a clean, modern look

# Open Chessame - Site | Github | Demo

An app that allows users to improve their chess openings

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Built a dynamic database including user info, openings, and games, which allows users to view nested data.
- Accessed the Youtube API to provide video instruction on opening moves.
- Employed Material UI to style components for a stunning in-browser experience.

# Beanies, Baby! - Github | Demo

An e-commerce site, which allows users to shop for Beanie Babies.

- Used RESTful routing on both the client and server sides to create an easy-to-use cart to hold purchases.
- Deployed a Sinatra back end with a SQL database to hold product information.
- Built a log-in system with validation on the Sinatra backend to confirm a user's identity.
- Used Semantic UI to style components for an eye-catching look.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Penguin Random House**

Alfred A. Knopf New York, NY **Assistant Editor** 08/2018 - 2021

- Edited books by both Knopf and Pantheon authors with a focus on style, content, and grammatical detail.
- Wrote compelling, engaging copy, which was used for in-house marketing, on Amazon, and the jacket.

# **Penguin Random House**

New York, NY

Alfred A. Knopf **Editorial Assistant** 

10/2014 - 07/2018

- Assistant to Vice President and Executive Editor
- Served as the point of contact for authors during the editing and production processes.
- Collaborated with literary agents, designers, legal consultants, publicists, and production staff to ensure that deadlines were met and the author's vision was supported.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Flatiron School**

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

04/2021 - 08/2021

**University of Chicago** 

Chicago, IL 06/2011

B.A. in Philosophy